# 福建 石狮市（地名）
(Shishi, Fujian)
# 来吃这边的花生汤吧
How about the peanut soup here?
# 等一下 很快就到你了
One moment
# 芋头
(Taro)
# 到你了
Your turn
# 我要一碗
I'd like one bowl
# 要加什么 加蛋吗？
Anything to add? An egg?
# 加蛋！还有芋头是吧
An egg. And is that taro?
# 有啊
Yeah
# 嗯 都要
Um. Both of them please
# 一份就够哦
Just one bowl?
# 嗯
Yes
# 多少钱
How much is it?
# 配什么？还要什么
What else would you like to add?
# 还要什么 配一根油条吧
What else... A youtiao I guess
# 对 一共多少钱
Yeah. How much?
# 6块
6 yuan
# 花生汤多少钱
How much is the peanut soup?
# 4块5
4.5 yuan
# 油条1块5
Yeah, 1.5 yuan for the youtiao
# 油条在后面哦
Youtiao is at the back
# 过去了
(Mobile payment) Paid
# （油条）在后面
It's at the back
# 油条 我们这里有袋子 自己拿
We have bags here. Help yourself with the youtiao
# 可以
OK
# 这个花生汤 真的很烫
The peanut soup is really hot
# 找到这个地方真不容易
It's not easy to find this place
# 花生汤是4块5一碗
A bowl of peanut soup costs 4.5 yuan
# 咱们要了一个油条来搭配吃
We paired it with a youtiao
# 其实我是不知道
In fact, I'm not very sure
# 花生汤到底应该和什么是标配
what peanut soup is supposed to be paired with
# 所以 按照我的习惯
So I just did it in my way that
# 要了一根油条
I took a youtiao
# 我们第一次喝花生汤
This the the first time we try peanut soup
# 看看花生汤里 有什么样的东西
Let's see what's inside the peanut soup
# 芋头是在锅底的
The taro was stewed at the bottom of the pot
# 叔叔把它捞上来
The uncle scooped it up
# 然后用剪刀把它稍微碾碎一些
and slightly mashed it with scissors
# 倒上花生汤
And then he poured the peanut soup over it
# 加上快煮烂的花生
and added those well stewed peanuts
# 你有没有发现 这个花生是白色的
Did you notice that the peanuts are white?
# 也就是说 花生是被提前去了皮的
In other words, they are peeled in advance
# 这个喝起来微甜
The soup tastes a little sweet
# 但是这种甜 是红糖的甜味
which is the sweetness of brown sugar
# 芋头在里面很绵软
The taro in it is very soft
# 在这边吃了很多次
We've had taro like this for many times here
# 这种比较粉 比较糯的芋头
Really tender, really soft
# 蛋花是用滚烫的花生汤冲出来的
The egg drops are made in boiling soup
# 顺滑而且厚实
Smooth and thick
# 而且
Besides
# 你回味一下汤的味道
the aftertaste is like
# 还能体会到花生这种坚果的香味
the nutty flavor of peanuts
# 炖的时间久
(It's been stewed for a long time)
# 这个花生汤是藏在一个隐蔽的菜市场里
This peanut soup booth is hidden in a farmers' market that's also hidden
# 一进来 你就会被它
As long as you enter it
# 比较露天的环境所震撼到
you'll be amazed by this open air environment
# 你在远处就能听到打蛋的声音
You can even hear the egg beating sound at a distance
# 我就是被这个打蛋的声音
It's exactly this egg beating sound
# 所吸引过来的
that attracted me to here
# 姐姐 我刚才没听清
Sis, I missed it earlier
# 大叔说 是从早上5点卖到几点啊
What did the uncle said about the business hours? From 5am to...?
# 下午5点
To 5pm
5pm
# 12小时
12 hours
# 嗯
Yeah
# 一天需要准备多少桶 才能足够卖
How many pots do you sell everyday?
# 一天 一般那种小桶
Everyday... Normally, for those small pots...
# 那种小桶
For those small pots
# 小桶一般在
It's like...
# 像这个时候 一般在16桶左右
Like about 16 pots in these days
# 16 桶左右
About 16 pots
# 一般早上来吃的人多一些
Is it more popular in the morning?
# 早上比较多
Yeah, more popular in the morning
# 这个一般作为早餐吗
So it's mostly sold as breakfast?
# 就是早餐
Yeah, it's a breakfast
# 那下午只是
In the afternoon, basically...
# 点心一下
It's a snack
# 有的老人家会过来当点心吃一下
Some elder people may come and have it as a snack
# 明白了
OK, got it
# 谢谢
Thanks!
# 关注雪鱼探店
(Subscribe)